There once was a peculiar doctor
曾经有一个独特的医生
known for his extraordinary ability.
以他非凡能力著称
He could talk to animals.
他可以与动物沟通
Doctor Dolittle's reputation
spread far and wide.
怪医多立特医生声名远扬
Even the Queen of England called on him.
连英格兰女王都召见他
So grateful for his help
女王赐予给他一座奇妙的庄园
she gifted him a wondrous sanctuary
以感谢他的帮助
whose doors were opened to all creatures.
庄园向所有生灵敞开了大门
His days belonged to the animals
多力特整天和动物在一起
but his heart belonged to one woman.
但是 他的心属于一个女人
Lily the Fearless Explorer.
无畏的探险家--莉莉
They traveled the globe
going on great adventures.
他们环游世界 进行伟大的探险
Defending creatures
who could not defend themselves.
保护弱小的动物
They made an extraordinary team.
他们打造了一个非凡的团队
Soon, that team became a family.
很快 这个团队成为了一个家庭
With Lily by his side
有了莉莉的陪伴
Dolittle never felt more alive.
多力特从没觉得如此有活力
Until one day she left on an adventure.
直到有一天莉莉去冒险
Lily died at sea.
却葬身海底
Heartbroken he locked the gates
of the manor
伤心的他锁上了庄园大门
and completely retreated from the world.
从此完全与世隔绝
As for me, and the animals
whose lives he'd saved
至于我和他救下动物
we were left to wonder
could anyone save his?
我们想知道 谁能救他
Until one morning, a most unlikely creature
found its way to Dolittle's life.
直到一天早上 一个最不可能的生物
找到了多力特
A very special boy.
一个非常特别的男孩
In a time when people thought of animals
当时人们认为动物
only as possessions, food, or sport
不过是财产、食物或者一个玩笑
this boy felt quite differently.
这个男孩感觉完全不同
This way, me scattered crew.
这样 我松散的队员
- Junior flushes him, you shoot, yeah?
-你弟弟冲出去 你开枪 行吗?
- Right. Good plan, dad.
-行 好的 爸爸
- Get ready. Shoulder your gun.
- Do I have to, uncle?
-准备好 抬起枪来
-我必须开枪吗  叔叔
Come on, boy.
来吧 孩子
Take that one. Shoot! Shoot!
打那只 开枪 开枪
Shoot! Shoot!
打 打
- I don't know, I can't.
- Shoot! Shoot!
-不行 我不能开枪
- 打啊 打
You can't keep missing on purpose.
你不能一直失手
Oh, look! He hit something this time!
看 快看 他打到了别的东西
Oh, no. We have to help him.
不 不 我们得救他
You don't leave an animal suffering.
如果不想让它痛苦
Take it.
了结了它
He's a very odd boy.
他是个很奇怪的男孩
Follow Poly.
跟着波利.
Home of Doctor John and Lily Dolittle.
怪医多力特·乔和莉莉之家
（地上跑的、跳的、天上飞的都接收）
We treat all animals--
我们对所有的动物……
Follow Poly.
跟着波利
Secret entrance.
秘密入口
Poly, where'd you go?
波利 你要去哪？
Good dog. Big, white--
乖狗狗 大……白……
It's no good.
大事不好
As far as I'm concerned
I'm the only human here.
据我所知 我是这里唯一的人类
Just ignore them.
别管他们
There's no getting past the Kalahari snare
it's an ingenious design.
没人能通过卡拉哈里陷阱 设计很巧妙的
I think you just caught yourself a boy.
我认为你只是抓住了一个男孩
Let me see. Wait, I don't wanna see.
Just make it go away!
让我看看 不 我不想看
赶快把他赶走
Deep breaths, Doc.
Dab-Dab's got your back.
深呼吸  有嘎嘎在 不用怕
Don't be afraid, John. It's just a boy.
约翰 不要害怕它只是一个男孩
This is an opportunity.
这是一个机会
This is a nightmare!
这是一场噩梦
Pardon me.
打扰一下
Whatever you're doing up there?
不管你在上面干嘛
I've come from Buckingham Palace
on urgent business.
我来自白金汉宫 在处理紧急事务
Can you tell me if this is the home
of John Dolittle?
你能告诉我这是约翰·多力特家吗
Who are you?
你是谁
You may call me Lady Rose.
And you are..?
你可以叫我萝丝小姐 你是……
Stubbins.
斯塔宾斯
Could you... help me down?
你能不能……帮我放下来
This goes against Dolittle's rules.
这会违反多力特规定的
Why are humans against the rules again?
人类为什么再次违反规定呢
If you let humans too close
you'll get hurt more
如果你让人类靠太近
than you would if you didn't let them
at all. Isn't that right, Doc?
你会受到更多伤害 对不对 医生
That's enough everybody. Back to our
routine! We have a very full day.
够了 都回去 今天够了
John, pull yourself together!
约翰 振作起来
You can't ignore people
just because they're... people.
你不能忽视人类 因为他们…是人
What if they need help?
万一他们需要帮助呢
Possum, play dead.
负鼠 装死
负鼠在躲避敌害时还有一个“装死”的绝招，十分灵验，可以迷惑许多敌害
This is ridiculous. Chee-Chee
will you answer the door?
这太荒谬了 吉吉 你去开门吗
You're the only one with arms.
你是唯一一个有手的
I think chess was enough pressure
for one day.
我觉得一天天下棋压力已经够大了
Chee-Chee boy.
This is what we trained for.
吉吉 是时候展示我们的训练成果了
Be brave and get rid of them.
勇敢点 去赶走他们
- And don't forget your mantra.
- I am not a prisoner of fear?
-不要忘记你的咒语 -我不是一个胆小鬼？
You are not a prisoner of fear.
你不是胆小鬼
Have you been here before?
你以前来过这儿吗
The Queen told me all about it.
It's the most unusual place.
女王告诉我了关于这的一切
这是一个最不寻常的地方
I'm prepared for anything.
我时刻准备着
Wonderful! A gorilla
answering the door.
太神奇了 一只大猩猩来开门
Just as the Queen said.
正如女王说
Wait a minute.
等一下
I have an injured squirrel.
我带来了一只受伤的松鼠
I should've never let you go.
我就不应该让你走的
Hello?
你好
Oh, look at you!
看 快看看啊
Aren't you peculiar
posing as a twig?
假扮成一根树枝
太奇特了
Move, please!
This is my hiding spot.
让一让 这是我的藏身之地
Not here.
这没人
Are you alright down there?
你还好吗
Yeah. I'm fine. Go on.
是的 我很好 继续
- Doctor Dolittle.
- Yeah, right.
-多力特医生
-对 是的
You have been summoned to
Buckingham Palace by the Queen herself.
女王亲自召见你
去白金汉宫
Go on.
接着说
You should know.
She's fallen gravely ill.
你应该知道 她身患重疾
Do you understand what I'm saying?
你明白我在说什么吗
那你明白我在说什么吗
Go... on.
Go on and be gone!
继……续…… 说完就走!
（英语“继续”和“消失”同音）
I don't care about anyone
anything anywhere anymore.
我再也不关心任何地方的任何人以及任何事
The birds will show you out.
鸟儿会带你出去
Great. Everything's tidy.
Lunch will be served in a minute now.
好极了 一切正常 马上供应午餐
- Smells lovely, Doc.
- Thanks very much.
- 怪医 闻起来很香啊
- 非常感谢
Hey Doc, save some
for us this time.
怪医 这次给我们留点
Sorry, Doc. Guess
I'm scared of kids, too.
抱歉 怪医 我觉得我也开始讨厌小孩了
Don't worry about that.
Come on. Let's eat.
别担心 来吧 来吃饭吧
For that we'll be offering today
a broccoli soup.
今日特供美食 西兰花汤
You'll never believe
what we caught in the net.
你不会相信的 我我们被网网住了
The Queen has asked for you
by name, sir.
先生 女王亲自召见你了
Are you hard of hearing?
I told you I'm closed for business.
你是有听力障碍吗
我说了我很忙
What business?
忙什么
Treating humans.
招待客人
Intruder alert!
入侵警报
- Don't worry, I'm fine.
- Well, I'm not!
-别担心 我很好
- 我可不好
My house is descended into chaos.
我家一片混乱
- Is it yours?
- I don't own anybody.
-那是你的熊吗
-我不占有任何人
Yoshi had an issue
that he came to me with.
耀西有麻烦所以才来找我
（耀西是《超级马里奥》里面的一只恐龙）
He's always cold.
他总是很冷
I have an injured squirrel.
我带来了一直受伤的松鼠
I don't know what to do.
我不知道该做什么
How was he injured?
他是怎么受伤的
- I shot him.
- Wha-- I can't hear you.
-我开枪射击了他 - 啥 我没听明白
I shot him, but it was an accident.
我射中了他 但那是个意外
Of course! An accidental firing upon.
当然了 擦枪走火吗
Humans never change.
人类永远不会改变
He's very hurt.
他很疼
Please help him.
请救救他
Take that. And this.
拿着这个 还有这个
I'm too beautiful to die.
我这该死的无处安放的魅力啊
Yes?
什么?
He's with us.
他还活着
Dab-Dab, Jip, light the lamps.
Disinfect the surgery.
嘎嘎 吉普 打开灯 准备手术消毒
You will not tend to a squirrel
英格兰女王命悬一线
while the Queen of England's life
hangs in the balance!
你不能去救这只松鼠
You don't konw me very well, do you?
你不太了解我 是吧
Don't drop him.
不要放弃它
We have a code red.
Code red. Code red everybody.
红色警报 红色警报 各位准备好
The Doctor is back!
怪医来啦
Hang on, little buddy.
小东西 挺住
- Haven't done this in a while.
- Let's get everything the way Doc likes.
- 有一阵子没干这个了
-一切按照医生的风格安排
Don't worry, we got you, pal.
小老弟 别担心 有我们在
Presume to save this squirrel, shall we?
拯救这只小松鼠 开始
Okay.
遵命
When you wake up
everything will be fine.
你醒来一切将安然无恙
If I die I swear
I will haunt your house.
如果我死了 我发誓我会阴魂不散
Sterilise the scalpels
do not lick any instrument--
给我无菌手术刀 不要舔别的东西
Patient's condition is stabilised.
患者情况稳定
They are understanding human
he's understanding them.
动物能听到他的 他也能听懂动物
In their own languages.
用他们自己的语言
Going through the left ventricle.
Breathe!
通过左心室 呼吸
Dab-Dab, forceps please.
嘎嘎 给我钳子
Here you go.
给你
That's a piece of celery.
Forceps, Doctor.
那是一根芹菜
医生 钳子
- Sorry. Here you go.
- Still, celery.
- 抱歉 给你
- 还是芹菜
- Forceps?
- Carrot.
- 钳子
- 胡萝卜
- Forceps?
- That's a different piece of celery.
- 是钳子吗
- 那是另一根不同的芹菜
- Got it. Forceps.
- No. Still celery.
- 在这 钳子
- 不 还是芹菜
Never mind. I'll get it myself.
算了 我自己拿
A human talks to the animals?
一个人跟动物对话
Chee-Chee, brow.
吉吉 擦额头
My brow as well
when you've got a second.
有空的话还有我的额头也擦下
Right. Sorry.
对哦 抱歉
I'm going to come here
and be Dolittle's apprentice.
我要到这里来
做多力特的学徒
Her Majesty has designated this land
in nature preserve.
女王陛下已经指定的这片土地
为自然保护区
If she dies...
如果她死了……
the deed will be owned by the Treasury
财政部将接手当年的赠送契约
and this place goes away.
这个地方将不复存在
Shut down?
关掉？
There you are.
拿出来了
Still got it, Doc.
行啊 怪医
There, Cheech. That's the spot.
这里 切奇 就是这 （切奇是美国喜剧演员）
Keep an eye on Kevin, should we?
我们应该看好凯文 对吧 （此处有梗）
He may be prickly
when the anesthetic wears off.
麻醉药效没了 他可能会变成刺猬
Revenge!
复仇
Okay. Okay. Enough
with the pampering.
好的 好的 贴身护理结束了
You need to go and help the Queen.
你要去帮助女王了
There are things I no longer do:
有些事情我不再去做
work with humans, or leave the house--
与人类合作或者离开这……
- Or bathe.
- Exercise.
- 还有洗澡 - 锻炼
Express emotional vulnerability.
以及表达情感的脆弱
Wake up, John! If the Queen dies
the Treasury takes the deed.
And we'll lose this house.
我们都会失去这个房子
You're talking out of your tail
feathers, Poly. The deed was for life.
你在放屁吧 波利 契约是一生
The last time I checked
I was very much alive.
上次我检查的时候我还很有活力
The Queen's life, John. Not yours.
是女王的一生 不是你 约翰
Look at that.
It just rolls off my back.
看看这个
从我背上滚下来了
I knew I shouldn't've let monkeys
proofread the contract.
我早应该让猴子去仔细甄对合同的
Elliot, Elsie, you are fired!
艾略特、埃尔希 你们被解雇了
It gets worse.
这变得更糟
We'll be thrown out of the gates
right in the middle of hunting season!
我们会在狩猎季被扔出大门的
What?!
- No, no. Breathe, Chee-Chee.
什么？！
-不 不 冷静 吉吉
We will be kicked out
if the Queen dies?
如果女王死了
我们会被踢出家门？
- We gonna be hunted.
- Everybody, calm down.
-我们会被猎杀
- 各位请冷静下
Look at the state of him now!
看看他现在的状态
Fear not. I have an inn
at Regent Park Zoo.
不要害怕 在摄政公园我有一家酒店
Everyone pack your bags!
大家收拾好行李
You help the Queen or we are leaving!
你去帮助女王或者我们离开
- You are bluffing!
- Don't make me count.
- 你在虚张声势
- 不要逼我倒数
Don't make me count.
你也不要逼我倒数
- One.
- 一
- Three.
- 三
Two...
二...
Alright! I'll do it.
好好好 我去
Let's get you ready to go, honey.
亲爱的们准备走
- I'll go as I am.
- Not looking like that.
- 我就这样走
- 不能这样子
- I'll just grab my doctor's bag.
- Get him!
- 就拿上我的医疗箱
- 抓住他！
Hold still now.
不要动
Get your paws off me!
把你的爪子从我身上拿开!
This isn't gonna hurt a bit.
这不会伤害到你的
- Let's clean him up.
- How dare you!
- 我们给他洗一下
- 你们敢！
- Hey guys.
- 你们好啊
- Arthur?
- 亚瑟?
- How long have you been living in there?
- I don't know. What year is it?
- 你住在那多久了？
- 我也不知道 现在是哪一年？
- Dab-Dab got the razor.
- That's still celery.
- 嘎嘎拿了剃须刀
- 那还是芹菜
Nighty night, Doc.
晚安安 怪医
Dolittle used to travel
around the world.
多力特曾环游世界
Look.
看
- Ravaging through my private projects?
- How is he?
- 偷看我的私人物件
- 他怎么了
First things first. The squirrel's name
is Kevin. Expect a full recovery.
先说重要的事 松鼠的名字叫凯文
预计会痊愈的
And after some violent grooming
it's been decided.
一番暴力的梳妆后
我们决定
We will come to you
to Buckingham Palace after all.
我们最终还是要去你白金汉宫
You are going back to whatever burrow
you emerged from.
你 回你爬出来的山洞里去
Try not to shoot anything
on your way home.
回家路上不要再射杀任何东西了
Maybe, I should stay here.
I don't do well in crowds.
也许 我应该留在这里
人多我感觉不太好
We'll look after you, Cheech. But we all
going together, just like the old days.
吉吉 我们会照看好你的
我们全都会在一起 像以前一样
- Don't forget doc's forceps.
- That's a leek, Dab-Dab.
- 不要忘了医生的钳子
- 这是一棵韭菜 嘎嘎
- Sure it is.
- Sticks.
- 我确定
- 木棍子
Where are you?
你在哪里?
So, would you care to come along?
所以 你要一起来吗
I know. I had other plans as well.
我知道 我有其他的计划
Hurry up. Hurry up.
快点 快点
Prepare my ride.
准备我的座驾
Today is gonna be a good day.
I'm gonna do nothing
今天是个好日子
打开了家门咱迎春风
just prance around
pick my own thoughts.
昂首阔步
随意而行
He's walking this way, not a great sign.
He's got no beard, he looks motivated.
他急冲冲过来了 肯定没好事
他刮了胡子 看起来很上进
Plimpton, don't be alarmed.
普林顿 不要慌张
People only say that when they are
about to be alarming.
人们只有在要慌张的时候才会这样说
Sorry about this.
And sorry about that.
抱歉咯 真抱歉
- Alright.
- I'm unavailable.
- 好吧 - 我不营业
Unavailable for the man
who changed your life?
一个改变了你生活的人也不营业？
- We're going to save the Queen, bro.
- I am not your bro!
- 老兄 我们要去救女王
- 我不是你的老兄
- You should be an Eskimo's rug by now.
- Ow, claws! Big claws.
- 你现在应该是爱斯基摩人的一条小毛毯子
- 哇 爪子 大爪子
Now now, Gentlemen.
不是现在 先生们
Oh, you've gained weight.
嗷 你胖了
Why are you riding me? There's
like four horses in front of us.
你为什么要骑我? 我们前面有四匹马
Cheer up, angry bird
kick back and enjoy the ride.
奥利给 愤怒的小鸟
放松并享受着旅程
I am the ride!
我是坐骑！
Buckingham Palace. We hit the big time.
白金汉宫 我们获得大成功了
Full speed no longer required!
不用再狂奔了
Welcome home, milady.
欢迎回家 夫人
Guards! Guards!
来人！ 卫兵！
Your Ladyship, Rose.
萝丝小姐
They are the Queen's own guests.
Treat them accordingly.
他们是女王的客人 好生招待他们
You better give me some
wide berth. Make way, boys.
你们最好给我一个宽敞的停车位 让路 孩子们
Plimpton!
普林顿 !
- Don't! Stop!
- Don't stop?
- 不要! 停! - 不要停?
- Alright, decision affirmative.
- Stop!
- 好的 不会停 - 停!
Can't see! Oh my God!
啊 我的天呐 我瞎了
Okay.
好吧
I blame the hat.
都怪那顶帽子
Doctor Müdfly.
穆德弗利医生
Lord Badgley.
巴杰利阁下
I come from the House of Lords.
我来自上议院
There is great concern
for Her Majesty's health.
女王陛下身患重疾
I shall continue to leech
我会继续用水蛭
to circulate the vapors
in the blood stream.
进行血液透析
She'll be lucky to last the week.
她应该撑不过这个星期了
This is not the first time
Dr. Dolittle's been here.
多力特医生已经不是第一次来这了
You got a dying Queen?
Not for long.
女王病危了？快走了？
Doctor Dolittle is in the...
多力特医生是……
- Wait. Wait for me.
- A stowaway, milady.
- 等等 等我 - 有个擅闯者 夫人
- Who claims to be--
- Doctor Dolittle's apprentice.
- 自称是 - 怪医多力特的学徒
It's quite alright, Gareth.
很好 加雷斯
（加雷斯是圆桌骑士之一，亚瑟王的侄子）
But if he was my apprentice
he should fetch my bags
但如果他是我的学徒 肯定会带着我的医疗箱
and keep his gob shut.
并且闭上嘴巴
Animals in the Queen's chamber?
有动物在女王的寝宫?
I demand their immediate remov--
我要他们立刻滚出去……
Lady Rose, my apologies.
萝丝女士 我深表歉意
Please forgive me. I didn't realise
that you were a part of...
请原谅我，我不知道你是……
John Dolittle.
约翰·多力特
- Is that Blein?
- 你是布林吗?
- Blair.
- 布莱尔
- Poofling?
- No.
- 浦弗林吗？ - 不是
- It was Muffler?
- No, it's Müdfly!
- 穆弗乐吗？
- 不 我是穆德弗利
- With an u-umlaut.
- Yes.
- 带两个点的U - 是吗
- From the German.
- Of course, from the Germans.
- 德语名字
- 当然了 德国人
Why is he here?
他为什么在这里?
Her Majesty has personally requested
Doctor Dolittle.
陛下亲自召见怪医多力特
Let's get to work.
Alright, Jip, give her a good sniff.
我们开始吧 吉普 给他一把宝刀
- You alright, fellow?
- Something smelled wrong.
- 怎么啦？老兄 - 闻起来不大对劲啊
And that's coming from a guy
who loves the smell of butts.
这是来自另一个人
他喜欢烟头的味道
- You do love butt.
- I detected a whiff of something else.
- 你的确喜欢那味道
- 我还闻出了一些其他的味道
Floral with ---
花香和……
I'm perplexed, Doc. I've never
smelt anything like it before.
我困惑 医生 我从来没闻过这样的
Jipsy and I have developed doubts.
May we consult?
吉普和我有些疑惑 我们能不能问下
Of course, I'd be more than happy
to help illumining...
当然 我很乐意帮你们
John and I were students
at Edinburgh years ago.
多年前 约翰和我在爱丁堡大学读书
Some thought he had a gift
for observation.
我们就觉得他有洞察生物的天赋
Sorry about that, Mini.
真抱歉 小小鼠
Stay here.
Dab-Dab, clear up the humans.
进去 嘎嘎 把人们先请出去
Boyo, fetch for botanic index
and the tea tin.
小伙 拿来*植物量度和茶叶罐
Everyone out! Do you understand
the words coming out of my bill?
大家都出去 听到没有 我都扇翅膀了
What do you smell, Jip?
Elderberries? Amoque?
你闻到了什么？
接骨木浆果吗? 阿莫克吗?
Negative?
不是吗?
Negative.
不是
Aye aye.
这个呢
What have you found, Dolittle?
多力特 你找到了什么?
Quite possibly
the answer to everything.
很大可能 什么都有
- Exposure--
- But he was like this in school.
- 这样啊
- 他在学校就是这样的
"Lean in, lean in...
I'm saying something interesting."
天灵灵地灵灵 快快显灵
I am interested.
我很感兴趣
The Queen symptoms are due to the effect
of a rare Sumatran plant
女王的病症可能一种苏门答腊稀有植物造成的
known as the Nightshade flower.
也叫夜影龙葵花
A solar eclipse will occur
on the 17th of this very month.
每个月十七号都会满月
If she is not received
the antidote by then, she will perish.
如果到那时还没有解药 她就会枯萎
Is that a Turner?
那是特纳吗?
Must be. What a fine painting.
肯定是 多好的一幅画
I say, Dolittle, what is your plan?
我想问 多力特 你的计划是什么?
The plan?
计划？
I suppose we do need one.
我觉得我真的需要一个计划
The Queen's only hope is the cure
女王唯一的希望
that's never been tested
就是一种从没有人试过解药
从一个无声无息的岛屿的上
from tree that's never been seen
on island that's never been found.
一棵不为人知的树上摘来的
Sounds ridiculous saying it out loud.
But regardless of that...
听起来很荒谬 但是不管……
We have no choice but to embark
on this perilous journey
我们没有选择的余地 只能开始这段奇幻冒险
to obtain the fruit of the Eden Tree.
去摘伊甸园树上的果实
What?
什么?
Eden Tree? Oh my, fantastic!
伊甸园树? 哦 太奇幻!
The Dolittles
with their Eden Tree island.
怪医多力特和他的伊甸园树
- Isn't it enough that your wife--
- 还不长记性吗 你妻子……
- Shut up, Blair!
- 闭嘴 布莱尔!
Sorry, I meant to say
lovely to see you again, Blair.
对不起 我的意思是说
很高兴的再次见到你 布莱尔
We are off now, ta ta!
我们启程！哒哒！
Its fruit is said to cure every malady
known to man, grant eternal life
据说那个果实可以医治每个女性
对于男人 可以长生不老
even restore the hair on your head.
甚至可以让你不再秃头
You must let nothing pass her lips
that hasn't been made and served by you.
解药还没有 你什么都不能跟女王说
- Clear?
- Yes, I'll see to it.
- 明白了?
- 明白了 我会留意的
That's us to the carriage. Jip, you need
to stay behind and guard the queen.
那我们就走啦 吉普 你需要待在女王身边守卫她
- Very important.
- Right. Guard-dog mode.
- 相当重要
- 遵命 哨兵模式已启动
Stand back everyone
while I secure the perimeter.
各位请退出警戒范围
Excuse me.
打扰一下
I do so admire how you don't give up.
我很佩服你持之以恒的精神
The Queen is counting on both of you.
女王就指望你们了
Good luck.
一帆风顺
Right. Chop chop.
There is a long voyage in front of us.
走 快 快 快 我们有很漫长的一段旅途
And the boat isn't gonna sail itself.
船不会自己扬帆起航
Deep breath, Yoshi.
别紧张 耀西
We haven't got all day.
我们得赶快
- Seems like she's filled up.
- 坐不下了
- Maybe we could squeeze in one more.
- 我们应该可以再挤挤
- Oh, no.
- Plimpton! I mean...
- 噢 不
- 普林顿 我说
One more stop, good fellow.
好鸟鸟 要记得停
I can't hear you
because I am not here.
不听不听 王八念经
I believe it's time
to go our separate ways.
我觉得我们要分道扬镳了
- I am going with you.
- Certainly not. Far too treacherous.
- 我要跟你一起走
- 没门 那又没有宝藏
- I'm your apprentice.
- You? No. No.
- 我是你的徒弟
- 你？ 不 不
Oh, you have an apprentice. You
don't need an apprentice and an ostrich.
嗷 你有一个徒弟
你不需要 那你也不需要一只鸵鸟
I'll go home.
那我回家了
I didn't want to be embarrassed
so I pretend you belonged.
我当时是不想让你尴尬
才假装认识你
I was helpful there, wasn't I?
我之前帮你了 不是吗?
The animals like me
I don't take up much space.
动物们喜欢我
我也不占用空间
I think I belong here.
我要跟着你
Don't make me go home. Please.
不要让我回家 求求你了
What is that around your neck? Move.
你领子上那是啥？ 进来
- I'm worried about the boy, Bethan.
- Give him time. Time is all.
- 我担心这个贝森
- 给他时间 时间会告诉你
We're hunters, Bethan. Hunters.
贝森 我们是猎人 猎人啊
It has a certain...
We hunt things, he frees things.
我们得……
我们得去打猎 猎捕动物
A rabbit, mice--
野兔 老鼠……
He carries spiders outside!
他却养着一只蜘蛛
Nobody likes spiders, not even spiders.
没人喜欢蜘蛛 别说蜘蛛……
I don't know
how your sister put up with him.
真不知道他妈是怎么教他的
- Poly? What are you doing here?
- Making sure you don't miss the boat.
- 波利? 你来干吗？
- 我来叫你登船
Am I talking to an animal?
Just like Dolittle.
我在跟动物说话？ 像多力特一样
Oh, no. I'm speaking human. Better
than any parrot ever has, actually.
嗷 不 是我在说人类的语言
其他鹦鹉都不会
Now, let's pack some clothes. Come on.
赶紧收拾行李走吧 快点
- But Dolittle said I belong here.
- Little help, Tutu.
- 但是多力特说我属于这里
- 帮帮忙 图图（梗：tutu芭蕾舞裙）
Well, I've never heard him say
anything of the sort.
我可从没听他这样说过
There's something special
about you, Stubbins.
斯塔宾斯 你很特别
Something I've only seen
in two other humans.
我只从两个人身上看到这种特殊性
You belong with us, kid.
孩子 你属于我们
And you let me worry
about Dolittle, that's my job.
你让我很担心多力特 那是我的职责
So, are you ready for the adventure
of a lifetime?
所以 你准备好你一生的大冒险了吗
- I'm in.
- Of course you are!
- 我来
- 当然了
Poly, let's move, we got a boat
to catch and we're burning daylight!
波利 快走吧 我们得连夜赶路登船
Fret not, Ma chéri,
we have the perfect plan.
别担心 亲爱的 我有一个完美计划
New plan! New plan!
新计划！ 新计划！
Don't let them get away!
别让他们跑了！
Why are they chasing us?
他们为什么追我们吗?
We're not criminals.
我们又不是罪犯
Speak for yourself, we're wanted
in three forests.
说起来 我们在三个森林被通缉
And it's not an escape mission
unless you're being chased.
现在是逃跑任务
他们在追捕我们
- I have to... - That tickles!
- 我必须 - 好痒啊
- Which way, Tutu?
- Down!
- 图图 走哪条路?
- 低头！
Clear the way!
让一让!
- This way!
- Get off the road, Ma chéri.
- 这边!
- 跳上去 亲爱的
See you later, suckers.
再见 憨憨们
We've done it!
We've done it! We...
我们到了！我们到了！我们……
...missed it.
……赶不上了
Okay, boss, what's our next move?
老大 接下来怎么办
We cut our loses, change our identities
ditch the kid in the river.
- Whoa, whoa. Easy.
- What about that bridge?
- 哇 且慢
- 那还有座桥?
Yes! The Bridge!
有了 上桥
- That was my next suggestion.
- Let's go!
- 那就是我的下一个提议
- 走！
Come on, Doc. At least
get out of the hammock.
来吧 怪医 至少从吊床上起来
Your sea sickness will wear off.
你就不会再晕船了
Try some of this ginger root. You'll get
your sea lights back. You look terrible.
吃点生姜 你就不会晕船了 你看起来很糟
Button it!
Who put me in this hammock?
拿过来！ 谁把我放吊床上的
I am the captain of this ship, mate!
水手们 我才是船长
Raise the blasting sails, will you?
升起风帆 可以吗
That's a big bite.
可真是一大口
Everyone, look. Is that the boy?
大家看啊 是那个孩子吗
He's coming to finish the job.
He won't rest till I'm dead.
他要来完成使命 我不死他不休
- He's obsessed.
- John, slow the boat down!
- 他着魔了 - 约翰 把船速降下来
- No. I wanna go faster.
- Sorry kid, John says no.
- 不 我要更快 - 抱歉 孩子 约翰不肯减速
- We're gonna miss all the good current!
- I hope they make it.
- 我们会错过的 - 我希望他们能上来
Me too, Dabs.
我也是 嘎嘎
All right, Bets, moment of truth.
来啦 现在赌一把 见证奇迹的时刻
Big hole, twelve o'clock!
十二点钟方向 有个大缺口
Maybe this is a bad idea.
这不太好吧
Let's go Stubbins! Let's go!
斯塔宾斯 冲啊 冲啊
I've run out of track!
我跳过障碍了
But not courage!
但大事不妙!
Fly, you big tree!
飞吧 ! 见证奇迹！
Vive la résistance!
抵抗组织万岁！
（法国抵抗组织，它的领导人就是后来的顶顶有名的戴高乐将军）
Is that thing up to code?
喊个口号这么厉害?
No!
不
不！
Jump, murderer. You got this!
跳吧 杀鼠凶手 你活该
I can't look.
不忍直视
No, no!
不 不!
Do it again, do it again!
再来一个 再来一个
Yes! Crossed it, kid.
You made it.
好样的 你飞过来 你做到了
Why y'all cheering for the kid
who shot me?
你们凭什么为射击的我的人欢呼？
He's alright.
他说得对
- Poly, can I have a word please?
- Glad you came around and saw things...
- 我能说一句公道话吗？
- 幸好你一路过来都看到了
What was she thinking?
The boy nearly killed himself.
她在想什么？这个孩子简直就是在自杀
Oy, this is my ship, right?
And I'm its sovereign.
哦哟 这是我的船对吧 我有主权
- And there are consequences--
- To ignoring me.
- 出了问题…… - 要忽略我
- Is that what you were going to say?
- No, no! Don't mess my words.
- 这就是你要说的？- 不不 不要误解我的话
- And stop messing with my routine.
- Look at the state of you.
- 不要再违反我的规定了 - 看看你现在的状态
- You're sick as a dog.
- Actually, I have my medicine.
- 你就像一只晕船狗一样 - 事实上我有晕船药
See? This licorice root is a treat!
看到没？ 甘草根就可以治晕船
Sit down, John!
坐下 约翰！
Don't embarrass me
in front of the crew!
不要在我的船员面前让我尴尬
I'm sparing you embarrassment.
You need a trim.
我在帮你解围 你需要训练
Alright, but quick.
It's important to maintain my status.
好的 但是要快点 我要保持我的地位
This ship is dangerous.
No place for a...
这艘船很危险 没有地方……
That's a private conversation.
这是私人对话
- Okay.
- Sorry.
- 好的 - 抱歉
I know this particular voyage is hard
for you, John. It is for me, too.
约翰 我知道这次特殊的旅行对你来说很难 对我也是
I brought to you Lily
just when you needed her.
我在你需要的时候将莉莉带到你身边
And now you need
one of your own kind again.
而现在你需要一个你的同类
Someone without feathers or fur.
一个没有羽毛或者皮毛的人
Fine, the boy can stay.
But it'll be on my terms.
行 那个男孩可以留下 但是我有条件
- And I mean to keep him quite busy.
- You'll do it with a smile on your face.
- 我要他一直在忙
- 你高兴就好
Crew, it seems you got a new shipmate.
船员们 你们有了一个新同事
As I just told Poly, we are
a bit short-handed after all, so...
就像我跟波利说的 我们人手短缺 所以……
- You won't regret it.
- Welcome aboard.
- 你不会后悔的！ - 欢迎登船
I hear you can be a big help
by clearing this out.
我听说你很能清理这个
That, too, if you don't mind.
Oops, those as well. And that.
那个也是 如果你不介意 喔 还有那个
- I got these.
- Careful with that medical equipment!
- 我来处理 - 小心那些医疗器械
Because a parrot's
in charge of my ship. Brilliant!
全都是因为一只鹦鹉在掌管我的船 棒棒的！
He's absolutely thrilled to have you.
他绝对是太期待你的加入了
Hello there, little squid.
You don't understand me, do you?
你好 小乌贼 你听不懂我说话 对吧
That would be preposterous.
那太荒谬的
- Müdfly.
- I wasn't talking to the squid!
- 穆德弗利 - 啊 我没有跟乌贼说话
I'm dispatching a frigate, the Britania.
我要派遣军舰 大不列颠号
To follow Dolittle.
去跟着多力特
You must not support him
in his foolishness, My Lord.
你不能支持他的白痴想法 阁下
England has enemies everywhere
waiting for the slightest sign of weakness.
英格兰所有的敌人都想趁虚而入
Entrusting beloved Britain
to a child queen?
难道要将英格兰交给一个没长大的女王？
That is lunacy.
愚蠢至极
So, while I remain here ensuring
no one prevents me from taking the throne
所以我在这确保不会有人篡位
you will be on the Britania
你去大不列颠号上
making certain Dolittle never returns.
确保多力特一去不复返
Round two, yeah! You got me on the rope
but you have to jab, Cheech.
第二轮 来 ！你已经把我按到边上了
但是你要猛出拳
Come on. One-two.
Jab. Jab. Pass.
来啊 一 二 出拳 出拳 躲
The best form of defense is attack.
最好的防守就是攻击
I really don't wanna fight you.
我真的不想跟你打
We are not fighting, are we?
This is a very practic session.
我们不是在打 我们是在实践练习
I think I'm getting this.
I'm actually starting to understand.
我觉得我能行 我真的理解了
Stop worrying, John.
君勿忧
Every step is planned out in my journal.
君在吾之道中计矣
I'll be back before you even miss me.
君思吾前吾即来之
Are you alright?
你还好吧?
I think I'm beginning to understand
a little bit of what the animals say.
我觉得我开始大概能听懂动物们说的话了
Seems you are, boyo.
我跟你一样 小伙子
What kind of polar bear works on their tan?
什么样的北极熊才会晒黑？
What kind of a bird...
那什么样的鸟……
- Wait, are you even a bird?
- Of course I am.
-  等等 你是只鸟？ - 当然啦
- Can you fly?
- No.
- 你能飞吗？ - 不能
- Can you swim?
- No.
- 你能游泳吗？ - 不能
- What can you do?
- I can run.
- 那你能干啥？- 我可以跑
- I can run. What bird stuff can you do?
- 我也可以跑 那你有个鸟用？
- What bear stuff can you do?
- 那你个又有个什么熊用？
You win this round.
这次算你赢
Pickles?
腌菜?
Oh, you are saying warship.
噢 你在说战舰
Weird, if you'd asked me for pickles.
Who could eat if we're under attack.
奇怪了 如果你跟我要腌菜 如果我们被攻击了还怎么吃
Enemy! Starboard aft! Elliot
you and Elsie, ready the machine.
敌人来袭 右舷船尾 艾略特 你和艾尔希去开动机器
We gonna need speed
send out the call!
我们得加速 发信号去
Secure the lifeboats!
This whole thing is a... death boat!
保护救生艇 这简直就是……死亡战舰
Stubbins, boy.
I need you now more than ever.
斯塔宾斯 我们现在非常需要你
- Just stand still.
- 站好了
- I surrender! We surrender!
-我投降 你们就投降
Hello, Blair, you chinless wanderer.
你好 布莱尔 你这个没有下巴的迷途怪客
He said something about my chin
didn't he?
他说我的下巴了 是吗
It's a magnificent chin, sir.
很明显是的 长官
We're in their sights.
Cannons are taking aim.
我们已经在他射程中 大炮正在瞄准
Let's turn this ship!
I'm on my way.
我来了
It is time for me to
slip into something less comfortable.
是时候 加入战斗了
I've bought a front row seat
to crazy time!
我这真是观看这个疯狂时刻的绝佳位置
Once Humphrey's been secured
you put me on to Yoshi's signal.
我一把鲸鱼套住 你就给普林顿发信号
Me? I can't handle
that type of pressure, Doc.
我？我受不了那么大的压力  医生
I'm a cheer-quietly-from-the-sidelines
kinda gorilla.
我是一只只会在旁边鼓掌的大猩猩
Don't worry, Cheech.
You'll rise to the occasion.
别担心 吉吉 你会抓住机会的
You're stronger than you know.
你比你想象的要强大
And remember
courage is not the absence of fear.
记住 勇气不是没有恐惧
Wait! You got cut off.
I can't hear you.
等等 ！你得摘下来 我听不到你说话
- I need the second part!
- No time, Cheech, let's go!
- 我需要听后面的！
- 没时间了 吉吉 我们走
Oh, look, look! They are already
abandoning ship.
噢 看呐 他要弃船了
Boom！
嘣！
This is gonna be cold.
But I'm coming in hot.
这会很冷 我来啦
Humphrey here.
汉弗莱在此
Let's hook it up.
开始拉！
- Where are we headed?
- South.
- 往哪边? - 南
Okay. I can do this. I can do this.
好 我可以的 我能做到
- Full steam ahead!
- Go, Humphrey! Go!
- 全速前进！ - 走 汉弗莱 走吧!
Are they pulling away?
他们在拉着船跑吗?
- Do it, whale! Do it!
- It's working.
- 加油 大鲸鱼 冲  - 能行了
How is this possible?
这怎么可能？
It appears Dolittle and a polar bear
have harnessed the whale--
看上去多力特和一只北极熊给一头鲸鱼套上了马具
It was a rhetorical question!
Just fire!
我那是一个夸张疑问句! 开火啊！
I dropped the rope!
啊 我拉不住绳子了
I failed, I knew I couldn't do it.
我失败了 我就知道我做不好
- Yoshi!
- Hang on! I'm coming, kid!
- 耀西！ 坚持住 孩子 我来了
- You're doing great.
- Oh, this is gonna murder my back!
- 你做得很好 - 嗷 这会扯断我的脖子
Quit complaining
you oversized flamingo!
不要抱怨了 你这个大号火烈鸟
Oh, no!
噢 不
Oh, no! Oh, no!
噢  不  噢 不
I let you down, Doc.
我让你失望了 医生
Look at me.
I'm fine. We're all fine.
看看我 我很好 你们都很棒
- I froze.
- No, Cheech. It's okay to be scared.
- 我当时愣住了 - 不 吉吉 恐惧不是什么坏事
You saved me, did you?
Fair play. Thanks very much.
你救了我 是吧 公平 谢谢你
Well-done everybody.
大家做得很好
Feel like you belong now, kid?
你觉得你现在属于这里了吗？孩子
I guess I do.
我猜是的
We lost them.
Great work, guys
干得好 各位
Eat our dust, Müdfly!
穆德弗莱吃败仗！
They've gone away, sir.
看不见他们了 长官
Oh, really? I thought
they disappeared into thin air.
噢 真的？ 我以为他们消失了
I'm afraid not, sir. They've escaped.
恐怕不是 他们逃走了 长官
Leave the room, Lieutenant!
I can see they've escaped.
滚一边去 中尉! 我知道他们逃走了
But not for long.
但跑不了多久
It's a miracle, that must mean
I am the chosen one.
真实个奇迹 这个肯定预示我是天选之子
I'm gonna change the wor--
我要改变世……
Whale power.
鲸鱼的力量
Dolittle had to write a paper about it
which, of course, nobody took seriously.
多力特肯定写在了纸上 当然 没人在意这些
This one even theorises
the existence of dragons.
甚至有龙存在的理论依据
Just preposterous.
一派胡言
Sir, I'm afraid your obsession
with Dolittle--
长官 恐怕你对多力特着迷了
What obsession?! I'm not obsessed with
Dolittle. You are obsessed with Dolittle.
什么着迷 我没有 你才对多力特着迷
You're the one obsessing
about my obsession with Dol--
我对杜立特着迷的事才让你着迷
I loathe to admit it
but he's more valuable alive for now.
我不想承认这一点 但是他现在活着更有价值
But, luckily, I think I know
where he's going.
而且 幸运的是 我知道他要去哪
Kevin's log, day seven.
I'm now totally isolated.
凯文日志 第七天 我已经完全被孤立
The enemy has ingratiated himself
with the captain and crew.
敌人讨好了船长和船员
No sign of promised tropical island
or the magic fruit.
没看到承诺的热带岛屿和魔法果实
But I will endure.
但是我会继续追寻
- Take the wheel, Stubbins. - Really? - Yeah, yeah.
- 斯塔宾斯 你来掌舵 - 真的？ -对 是的
I have to calculate our route coordinates.
The bees are buzzing about you.
我要计算我们的路线坐标 蜜蜂围着你嗡嗡嗡地
Seems you are getting
a rudimentary grasp of their language.
看起来你已经初步掌握它们的语言了
Thirty five degrees fore side.
前方转三十五度
I've noticed when they fly
in a zig-zag pattern.
它们呈之字形飞的时候我就提醒你了
They sort of go...
它们这样……
Which means "back off, kid."
意思是 退后 小子
But when Dab-Dab goes...
但是嘎嘎这样……
That means "look at this."
意思是 看这里
- "Look at me."
- Oh, close.
-  是 看我 - 噢 差不多
Not bad, though.
还好
When Chee-Chee says...
吉吉说……
That means... "Where is my blanket?"
意思就是 我的毯子呢
Very good.
真棒
Is that the map to Eden Tree island?
这是去伊甸园树岛的地图吗？
The Eden Tree
cannot be found on any map.
伊甸园树在地图上找不到
At core it's an island
is as suggestive as the whole world.
核心是岛屿 其实暗示着整个世界
And it is anything but.
是天生万物
That is why we must first go
to Monte Verde.
这就是为什么我们要先去蒙特沃德
Birthplace of the only person
to ever chart course to the Tree.
唯一一个指明神树方向的人的出生地
Her name was Lily.
She wrote the route in her journal
她叫莉莉 她记在了日记里面
but on her voyage
she was shipwrecked.
但她在航行的时候遇到了海难
The world lost the greatest explorer
I've ever known.
世界上最伟大的探险家就这样陨落了
The journal from that expedition
is all that survived.
那本日记还在
Elliot, Elsie, do you mind?
艾略特 埃尔希 能不能安静会？
So, anyway, you get the picture.
To have any chance of finding the Tree
不管怎么样 要拿到图纸 找到伊甸园树
we have to go to Monte Verde
and steal that flippin' journal.
我们得去蒙特沃德偷菲利普日记
- Steal the journal?
- Did I say that?
- 偷日记? - 我说了吗?
Well, what's the worst that can happen?
好吧 最坏的情况会是怎样？
Don't worry, I know an omen when
I see one. And that was not an omen.
别担心 我知道一个征兆就是我看到一个征兆的时候什么都不会发生
Stealing the journal is not a big deal.
偷人家的日记不是一个大事
In fact
Monte Verde itself is not a big deal.
事实上 蒙特沃德本身并不重要
The stop at Monte Verde
was a very big deal.
蒙特沃德很重要
After all, this island
of bandits and thieves
毕竟 这座全是土匪和小偷的岛屿
was once a place Dolittle
Lily and I called home.
多力特和莉莉称之为家
Until the Doctor made an enemy
of the island's notorious ruler
直到多力特与这座岛屿上臭名昭著的统治者为敌
King Rassouli.
拉苏利国王
And just our luck
his most prized possession
更巧的是 他最宝贵的财产
was the very journal
we needed to steal.
就是我们要偷的日记
So, Dolittle needed a disguise.
因此 多力特需要伪装一下
While I was left watching over
the rest of the crew
我留下来照看其他船员
Dolittle and Stubbins
snuck into the palace.
多力特和斯塔宾斯偷偷溜进宫殿
I'm about to die!
我要死啦！
Once inside, their path ended
at a heavily bolted door, naturally.
进去之后 门被闩上了
But, Dolittle still had...
但是 多力特仍然有……
questionable contacts on the island.
值得怀疑的关系
The opening bid will suffice.
You have my attention.
报酬足够丰富我就办事
Don Carpenterino, I am here
on behalf of these humans
别这样 我代表这些人类来跟你谈判
they will pay you handsomely
for your family's lock-picking skills.
他们会为你家族出神入化的开锁技术支付酬劳的
You come to me for this
on the day of my daughter's wedding?
你在我女儿婚礼这天来找我
Wait a minute, which daughter?
等一下 哪个女儿？
It's not... Sheila? My Sheila?
不是吧……希拉? 我的希拉?
She's getting married?!
她要结婚了？！
To a scorpion named Dylan.
很抱歉 嫁给一个叫狄伦的蝎子
Sorry, boy scout
I guess Sheila's into bad boys now.
我觉得希拉要嫁给一个坏蛋了
We were gonna spend
the rest of our lifespans together.
我们余生将天各一方
Hold on, James. What's
your human's best offer?
等下 你们人类能给与什么报酬
Two now, and two later.
现在两块 事成后再两块
Okay, you have yourself a deal.
See you around, boy scout.
好 那就这样成交 回见 侦察兵
Guys. I'm no boy scout.
兄弟 我可不是侦察兵
Also, what that scorpion got that
I don't got? Besides a massive stinger.
还有 蝎子有什么东西我没有呢？除了那个尾刺
Get over it, James
you dated for two weeks!
别在意了 詹姆斯 你约了两个星期了
These bars are new.
这几根铁杆是新的
- Totally messing up my plan.
- 完全扰乱了我的机会
- I can fit through them.
- 我能穿过去
No, no. It's too dangerous, man.
不 不 太危险了孩子
Can't go in there on your own.
你不能亲自过去
怪医 我去
Let me take him in, Doc.
I need something to distract me
from this Sheila reveal.
我需要做点别的让我不再想着我的希拉
Are you sure your head's
in the right place, James?
你考虑清楚了？詹姆斯
Oh, yeah! I'll get the kid in
and then fly head first into a brick.
噢 当然了 我飞进去 然后在砖块里面产卵
Just kidding, I'm fine.
开玩笑 我很好
Alright. James will look after you
it's fine.
好吧 詹姆斯会照应你
Listen closely, get the journal
you get out of there.
仔细地听好 你拿到日记 然后逃出来
Go through the room quietly
look for the tiger's eye.
悄悄地通过房间 注视着老虎的眼睛
Go down the hidden staircase, and most
然后从隐藏的楼梯上下去
importantly, keep your disguise on.
最重要的是要伪装好
There's just one little thing
you should know.
还有一件事你必须清楚
Rassouli loves his cats.
拉苏利国王非常喜欢他的猫
But, that's no problem for us
because we can just fly right over...
但是没关系 因为我们可以飞过去
Oh, I see the mistake
I made here. You can't fly.
噢 我错了 你不会飞
Watch out, kitty-kat on your six.
喔 小心 猫咪在你的六点钟方向
Oh, God!
噢 我的天啊
Slick move, kid.
轻点 孩子
We make a pretty good team.
我们真是完美搭档
A real couple of bad boys.
一对真正的坏小子
Okay, partner, you know where to go.
好的 伙伴 你知道从哪走
I'll keep watch on these lions
我来看着这些狮子
that's what a bad boy dragonfly does.
这才是一个坏小子蜻蜓该做的
Would Dylan get this close to a lion?
狄伦有本事靠近狮子吗？
Would he get this close?
他能这样近吗？
How about this close?
这样近呢？
Oh, shit!
噢 该死
This is bad... This is... very bad.
不妙 这非常不妙
Lily... Dolittle.
多力特·莉莉
We got the journal, open up!
我们拿到了日记 开门！
Just kidding, he blew it. Bye.
开玩笑 他搞砸了 拜
Oh, dear! Stubbins!
噢 我的乖乖 斯塔宾斯！
Don't let him get to...
不要让他进……
- Former resident here.
- Don't move!
- 我是原居民 - 不许动
Don't touch.
不要碰
All I wanted was my daughter
to marry wisely
我想要的不过是我女儿嫁个好人家
and instead I got the ring leader
of a circus.
而我现在确实个马戏团的头头
I never understood
what Lily saw in you.
我从不理解莉莉看上你什么
A common complaint the world over
for fathers of beloved daughters
全世界都在抱怨我这个爱女心切的父亲
but in this instance I think we can
但是现在我们不得不承认
all agree it is particularly accurate.
他们的抱怨的确很对
Come here.
过来
- Come here!
- Perhaps, you didn't mean any of that--
- 过来！- 也许这并不意味着任何……
It was her journal.
那是她的日记
The only thing of hers
my men found in the wreckage.
我的人在沉船中找到的唯一的遗物
It belongs here!
它属于这里！
All you had to do
was never show your face again.
本来你要做的就是从此消失
And even at that you failed.
即使那样你也没做到
Now you will pay
for taking Lily away from me!
现在你要为把莉莉从我身边夺走付出代价
You knew what would happen
if you returned.
你清楚如果你回来会怎样
Yes.
是吧
Barry, Barry!
巴里 巴里!
You should go.
你快走
It's my past that's caught up with me
not yours. Yeah?
那是我的私人恩怨 不是你 明白？
- You're my friend.
- Go. Don't look back.
- 你是我的朋友 - 快走 不要回头
You're better off without him, kid.
孩子 你最好别管他了
I'm in compliance.
我服！
Yes! Finally, some action down here!
Boy, it was getting boring.
耶！ 这里有有好戏看了！老兄 你上啊
You know, Doc, I hate to tell you
but you're going down, my friend.
怪医 你知道的 我虽然不想告诉你 但是你要完了
You'll do well to keep
your buck teeth together!
你最好把你的龅牙闭起来！
What is that smell? Hey, fellas, I think
Doctor Dolittle did a little doo-doo.
那是什么味？ 嘿 兄弟们 我觉得多力特多厉害
Did Doctor Dolittle do a little doo-doo?
小多力多厉害 小多力多能耐？
Perhaps, when I'm out of here
I'll teach you some manners.
也许 等我出去我会叫你怎么做兔
And accept your lucky foot as payment.
然后卸了你的红烧兔腿作为学费
Oh, this lucky foot?
Don't worry about it, Doc.
嗷 这只吗？想得美啊你 怪医
'Cause both of my lucky feet
are gonna be tap dancing on your grave
我这两只腿会在你的坟头跳舞
when my guy's done with you.
当我的兔兄教你做人后
Taking bets over here. In the right
corner, wearing golden stripes
现在开始下注  这边是穿金色条纹
with a sparkling record of 872 kills
保持872杀记录的
Barry 'The Butcher' Burnstein.
巴里 屠夫 巴里 巴里
Doctor Dolittle, remember me
your old patient?
怪医多力特 你还记得我不？ 你的老患者？
It's Barry.
我是巴里
Barry, how could I forget you?
巴里 我怎么可能忘了你
Oh, but you did, Doc. We were
just starting to make progress.
噢 但你的确忘了 当时我们关系正好
And then you ran off with
Rassouli's daughter and abandoned me.
你却抛弃了我 和拉苏利的女儿跑了
Well. I'm back now. Perhaps we should
just pick up where we left--
好吧 我现在回来了 也许我们应该继续……
Enjoy the feast!
吃好喝好！
What will happen to Dolittle?
多力特会怎么样？
Well, he's a dead man.
他啊 他死定了
He'll think he can talk
his way out of it
他会觉得他能跟动物说话就能活着
but Barry has gone completely nuts.
但他会惹毛巴里
But you, you are one of us now.
而你 你现在是我们的一员了
To Dolittle's death!
欢庆多力特之死!
Hey! It's you! You made it.
嘿 是你 你还活着
I need you to get a message
to my friends on the boat.
我需要你去给船上的朋友捎个口信
A message? Sure.
When have I ever let you down?
口信 ？可以 我什么时候让你失望过
All I hear day after day
"Oh, Barry, you're such a disappointment.
自那之后 他们都说 巴里你太令人失望了
Why can't you be more like your brother?
你为什么不像你哥哥那样？
He eats poachers for a living, you know."
他靠捕食偷猎者为生
Yes, Mother, I know!
是的 母亲 我知道!
The whole jungle knows!
整个丛林都知道!
Oh, my head.
嗷 我的脑袋
Your migraines are brought on
by severe maternal issues
你的偏头痛是你母亲导致的
and compounded by sibling rivalry.
还有兄弟姊妹的竞争
- Please, make it stop.
- Oh, no, no!
- 拜托 让它不要疼了 - 噢 不 不 不好
- Lie down.
- Oh, my head.
- 躺下 -嗷 我的脑阔
We could resume your treatment.
我可以继续给你治疗
The stress is unbearable.
我实在太难了
I just want to be a good boy.
我只想做个乖孩子
Just want to make Mommy proud.
只想让妈妈以我为傲
Yeah?
是吗？
No one I eat will ever be good enough.
我吃的都是些坏人
There's the release, release it.
想开点 想开点
I will never be good enough.
我绝不会变得足够优秀
Unless I eat you.
除非我吃了你！
Because every mother wants their son to grow up
因为每个母亲都希望自己的孩子长大了
and eat a doctor.
吃掉一个医生
You're a sick kitty.
你这只病喵
Come here, Doc.
I'll make it quick.
下来吧 医生 我会很快的
I've got another one of these
in an hour.
我还有下一场宴席要赶
Give up, Dolittle. You can't outsmart--
放弃吧 多力特 你不可能用计谋打……
What was that?
Wait. Now it's over there.
喔 那是啥？在那
And now it's over here.
现在在这
Now it's back over there, got it!
And now it's over here.
现在又跑到这里了 抓住了！又跑了
Oh, I lost it. I've got to get it--
喔 我抓到了 又没了……
A cat is still a cat. Easily distracted.
猫始终是猫 很容易分散它注意力
New game, Doc. Get back here.
来点新把戏！ 医生 给我下来
Come on, Doc!
下来吧 医生
Okay, James, you can't let this kid
down. You gotta deliver this message.
好的 詹姆斯 你不能让孩子失望
你必须把信送到
Oh, no. It's James.
噢 不 詹姆斯来了
From now on no more
focusing on relationships and...
从现在开始 不要关注人际关系和……
Poly? Is that you?
Your feathers really filled out nice.
波利? 是你吗？你的羽毛真的很漂亮
- What happened, James?
- Oh, right! Message. My bad.
- 怎么啦？ 詹姆斯  - 噢 对啦 口信
The kid's been captured by Rassouli, and
Barry is about to have Dolittle for lunch.
那个孩子被苏拉利抓住了
多力特快要被巴里吃了
Looks like we're going ashore after all.
看样子我们最终还是要靠岸
Be a darling, and grab my dynamite
will you?
乖乖听话 拿上我的炸药 可以吗？
We need to split up
if we are going to pull this off.
如果我们上岸 我们要分头行动
Chee-Chee, you're coming with me.
吉吉 你跟我一起
Where are we going?
No, no, don't tell me.
我们去哪？不 不 不用说了
Just tell me when we get there.
告诉我什么时候到就行
- Yoshi, create a distraction.
- Hope this is enough.
- 耀西 你去吸引注意力 - 希望这些够了
We are being attacked!
我们被攻击了！
- Come on down, Doc.
- Therapy's the answer!
- 医生 下来 - 要我给你治疗吗
Oh, no! Worse than I expected.
噢 不 比我预期得还糟糕
- I got you, Doc.
- Back off, Barry!
- 我抓到你了医生 - 退后 巴里！
Poly, don't!
波利 别！
An appetizer?
开胃菜?
I got you, Poly.
我来了 波利
Any final diagnosis, Doc?
有什么遗言吗？ 医生
Don't you want to be
the best Barry you could be?
你难道不想做最好的孩子了？
I'm about to.
我马上就是了
I am not a prisoner of fear!
我才不是一个胆小鬼！
- Oh, no, no, no!
- 我不是胆小鬼！ - 噢 不 不 不
It's okay to be scared!
恐惧很正常
- It's okay to be scared!
- You should be scared!
- 恐惧很正常！- 你的确应该恐惧
It's okay to be scared!
恐惧很正常
Give him a good hiding!
胖揍他一顿！
Okay. We're doing this.
We are doing this!
好的 我们揍他！ 揍他！
We're not doing this!
我不想揍他！
Hit him in the low area!
攻他下盘
Down there.
下……面……
- That's gotta hurt.
- Ow, my Barry berries!
- 那会很疼 - 嗷呜 巴里的蛋蛋
That will work.
奏效了
Cheap shot, ape.
卑鄙手段 猩猩
I haven't finished by treatment.
我的偏头痛还没治好呢
Go to sleep, baby tiger.
睡吧睡吧 小老虎
Time to put those claws away.
放开你的爪爪乖乖睡
Anyway.
还好
You need this more than I do.
你比我更需要这个
Tell me that I'm enough, Mommy.
妈妈 我够优秀了吗？
I had fifty grand running on that.
我押了五万元呢
Well, I won't pay that.
好吧 反正我不会给钱的
Ladies and Gentlemen, we have a winner.
先生们 女士们 冠军在此
Thanks for sticking with me, Doc.
医生 感谢与你同在
- I have it. I have this.
- Hold!
- 我拿到了！ 拿到了！ - 站住！
And now, I'll have it.
现在归我了
She had such a sure hand.
她手笔真好
Exactly what the doctor ordered.
医生说得对
What did they offer you, Müdfly
to murder the Queen of England?
穆德弗莱 谋杀英格兰女王 你有什么好处？
Quite a few things, actually.
的确有些东西
Knighthood. Windward house.
Chair of the Royal College.
爵士头衔 迎风城堡 皇家学院主席
In no particular order.
不分先后
Oh, and the icing on the Madeleine
噢 还有在*玛德琳岛上
will be the scientific accolades
that accrue
由伊甸园神树提取的科学研究成果
from the proper study
of the Eden Tree.
将是我的荣耀
All thanks to Lily Dolittle.
Actually, no. That's still Madeleine.
全都得益于多力特·莉莉
The icing is knowing
that you know I won.
我赢了
Oh, and Dolittle, I'm so sorry
for that hole in your boat.
噢 多力特 很抱歉你船上的洞
What hole?
什么洞？
Abandon ship! Everyone overboard!
弃船！ 大家快跳水！
Not good.
糟糕
Hold on!
抓住了！
- Help!
- I'm on it, Dab.
- 救命！ -我来了 嘎嘎
I can't fly... and I can't swim.
我不会飞……也不会游泳！
I got you, buddy. Plimpton?
I'm not losing you, bro.
我抓住了你 兄弟 普林顿？我不会放弃你的
- Step away from the light!
- There is no light! I'm alive! I'm alive.
- 别进天堂！- 没有天堂！ 我还活着！活着的！
I'm alive. Thanks to you, Yoshi.
我还活着 谢谢你 耀西
You've always been so kind.
一直都很善良
It's difficult to say goodbye.
离别总是这么难
Please don't say that.
别这样说
It's alright.
没事
You've done your best.
Your Queen is proud.
你做得很好了 我以你为傲
Where are you Dolittle?
多力特 你在哪？
Hey, big bird, you're doing okay?
嘿 大鸟 你还好吧？
No. Nothing about me is okay.
不 我一点都不好
My father was right about me.
我父亲说得对
- I should've been an omelet.
- 我真应该成为一盘蛋卷
- I know how you feel.
- 我理解你的感受
My dad said he was going
for a pack of seals one night
我父亲说他出去捕海豹
and never came back.
就再也没回来了
I guess we got something in common
after all, Plimpton.
我想这就是我们的共同点了 普林顿
What is this feeling?
I'm all warm and fuzzy inside.
那是什么感觉？ 我一直温暖舒适
That's friendship, bro.
那就是友谊 老弟
Not bad.
还行
Bro.
老哥
I'm not crying, you're crying.
我没哭 是你在哭
Right. Gather around, shall we?
好 我们团结起来
Let's have a look where we are now.
看看我们现在在哪
That's the spirit, John.
约翰 这就是精神所在
This is gonna be good.
一起都会好起来的
I'm already getting duckbumps.
搞得我都起鸭皮疙瘩了
- We are finished.
- What?
- 我们完了 - 什么？
Is this a pep talk?
'Cause it's a weird one.
这是鼓舞士气吗？ 真是奇怪
I can sniff defeat like a truffle pig.
我可以像松露猪一样嗅到失败
This can't be the end.
不能就这样
- Yeah. I suppose.
- We can still save the Queen.
- 是的 我不信 -我们仍然可以救女王
- No.
- We can still save your house.
- 不能 - 我们仍然可以保住你的庄园
I believe in you.
我相信你
- We can keep coming.
- You got a point there.
- 我们可以继续赶路 - 说到点子上了
Except the journal's gone.
We have no way to find the Eden Tree.
除了被拿走的日记 我们不知道哪里还能找到伊甸园树
- And our boat is sunk.
- He makes a strong argument.
- 而且我们船压迫沉没了 - 他说得很在理
On the plus side, you are all cured.
再说了 你们都治好了
Chee-Chee, you are brave now.
Plimpton and Yoshi are getting along.
吉吉 你现在勇敢了 普林顿和耀西也相处甚欢
- Remember back? Back.
- Sort of.
- 嗷 我的背 我的背 - 还有
And Stubbins, you've made friends
and you can even talk to them.
斯塔宾斯 你也有可以交谈的朋友了
You don't need me.
你不再需要我
I'll stay here and offer medical services
to this island of random bandits and outlaws.
我要待在这 给这岛上的强盗和歹徒治病
The doctor's here
seeking new patients! Cash only.
怪医在此 新寻病患 急症优先
Ladies, Gentlemen
who would like to dance?
女士们 先生们 谁想跳舞？
I got a bad case of dancing fever
so, watch out, it's infectious.
我患上了跳舞狂热病 小心 会感染
Can't help him.
得帮他
The explorer you told me about
she would've never given up.
那个探险家告诉我她绝不轻言放弃
- She was your wife, wasn't she?
- You wanna know the ironic bit?
- 她是你的妻子 对吧？ - 你想知道这有多讽刺吗？
I don't know what ironic means.
我不明白怎么讽刺了
Irony is when you find a woman
就是你找到一个心上人
and she makes your life more wonderful
than it ever had the right to be.
她令你的生活多姿多彩
And then poof, she's gone
and it's all your fault.
然后嘭的一下 她走了 而且都是你的错
This journey was my chance
to finish what she started.
这次旅途我就是要完成她的遗愿的
Lily insisted I cared for the animals
at home, so I stayed behind.
莉莉坚持要我在家照顾动物 所以我留下来了
Rassouli's right.
I should've been with her.
拉苏利说得对 我不该离开她
All I have left of her is a ghost I see
when I hold our rings.
我戴上我们的戒指就会看到她的灵魂
So, you see her, too?
所以 你也看到她了？
Not only did you lose
my daughter's journal
你不仅弄丢了我女儿的日记
but your polar bear blew up my village.
你的北极熊还砸了我的村庄
We don't know that.
我们怎么不知道
And your gorilla beat up my tiger.
你的大猩猩还打了我的老虎
No good.
真糟糕
Let's go.
我们走
No, no.
不 不 不
Irony... is me
讽刺的是……我
wanting to kill you
with every fiber of my being
想用尽我全身的力气杀了你
but...
然而
...loving my daughter more.
……我更爱我女儿
I miss her, too.
我也想她了
She would've wanted you to...
她也会想让你……
to keep going.
坚持向前
So!
那么！
Keep going
继续前行
Befor I stop feeling sentimental.
在我停止多愁善感前
She's saying we don't have a ship.
她说我们没有船
Well...
这……
I have the perfect vessel for you.
我有一艘大船给你
A bit of a fixer-upper.
He's got... good boat.
还能修 也是条……好船
At least it flows.
至少还能浮
We'll just have to make
the best of it, won't we?
我们要好好利用它 是吧
- Company!
- Who's that?
- 有人！ 啊 是谁？
Hi, I'm Jeff.
嗨 我是杰夫
Crikey!
哎呀！！
If Lily's research was correct
如果莉莉的研究是正确的
and Müdfly was well on his way
to Eden Tree island
那穆德弗莱就会去找伊甸园树岛屿
all we needed to do was track Müdfly.
我们只要追踪穆德弗莱就可以
But how do we do that?
但是我们怎么才能追踪他？
Whales, boyo. Whales.
鲸鱼 孩子们 鲸鱼
- I can't believe you're flipping him off.
- 我不信你居然找到他了
- I know, that man has no chin.
- 我知道 他没有下巴
We found him. Follow us.
我们找到他了 跟上
Eden Tree island.
伊甸园树岛
Extraordinary.
非同寻常
This must be it.
肯定是这
The map points us directly
into the centre of this mountain.
地图上标注了就在这座山中央
Don't look down. Let's keep
our beaks up, shall we?
别往下看 手拉手 行吗
Trying to stay positive. But
what the heck are we doing up here?
努力保持乐观 但是我们在这个该死的悬崖上干嘛
Going the back way
my feathered buddy.
跟着我们 毛毛兄弟
What are you complaining about? This is
the widest branch I've ever scurried on.
你在抱怨什么 这是我走过最宽广的路了
Don't look down. Look at me.
别往下看 看着我
Whoa. A big cave.
哇喔 好大一个洞
Stay close. Keep quiet.
保持安静 跟紧了
Kevin's log. Day 12.
凯文日志 第十二天
Some force beyond my comprehension still
compels me to follow this crew of lunatics
一股超乎我理解的力量逼我跟随着这群疯子
the squirrel killer
and their deranged leader.
松鼠杀手和他的老大
Perhaps, it's the magic tree
that draws me.
也许 是魔法树吸引着我
Hide, they're close.
躲起来 他们在附近
Now stay down.
小鼠鼠 快进去
Foxfire rocks.
火狐岩石
We must be near it now.
我们肯定快找到了
Look, Doc.
看呐 医生
It's lighting a path all the way to...
豁然开朗 一路向……
the man who wants us dead.
想要置我于死地的人
Stay right there!
待那别动！
Go on then, soldier boy.
Spoil it yourself.
来吧孩子 拿你的战利品
Hello, Blair.
你好啊 布莱尔
- Get over there!
- Looking for a Tree, is it?
- 滚那边去！ - 在找那棵树是吧？
Trees don't often grow in caves. Didn't
树不会长在洞穴里
you pay attention to botany class?
生物课没认真听吧
No! But pay attention to this, Dolittle.
对！ 但是请认真听这个 多力特
I beat you.
我抓住你了
- Filthy animal.
- Let go!
- 恶心的动物！ - 我们走！
Order!
安静！
So.
那么
- Where is it?
- Where's what?
- 在哪？ - 什么在哪？
- The Eden Tree.
- 伊甸园园树
- Truth is... I haven't got a clue.
- 事实就是……我没有线索
（《钢铁侠1》里面妮妮也是这个口气这样说）
Don't be ridiculous, you're John Dolittle.
别开玩笑了 你是约翰·多力特
You get everything you want.
你能得到所有你想要的
Not today I don't.
没开玩笑 我没有得到
You really don't have any idea, do you?
你真不知道吗？ 真的？
How does ignorance feel?
愚昧无知感觉怎么样？
Very freeing, actually.
其实还蛮自由的
One must hug uncertainty
don't you think?
一个人必须接受不确性 不是吗？
That's how Lily lived her life.
这就是莉莉的人生信条
And brace the unknown and...
拥抱未知
the answers will be revealed.
答案自现
You sad, misguided nut, Dolittle!
你这个愁眉泪眼	误入歧途的怪人 多力特！
Give that to me! Give me that!
给我 把旗给我
I will find this damn Tree on my own!
我会自己找到这棵该死的树
And by God, history will remember me!
天地可鉴 我将载入史册
Yes. Something interesting
is going on now.
是啊 现在好玩的来了
It rather feels a lot larger
than all of us.
这看起来比我大得多了
Look out!
小心！
Down here, the lot of you! Come on!
下来 你们全都下来 赶快
Stay down!
趴下！
He saved me. I have a second chance...
他救了我 我还能再次……
to live a life of kindness
and generosity.
善良、慷慨地活着
Take him, not me.
I am a good person now.
咬他 不要咬我 我是个大好人
I think we can make a run
for that ditch. Once it's--
我觉得我们可以跑过那条沟去 一旦它……
- Yoshi!
- Get this off of me.
- 耀西！- 把这玩意儿从我身上拿开
- Cheech.
- Help me, Plimpton.
- 吉吉 - 救救我 普林顿
- I'll save you, bro.
- Right, John, think fast.
- 老兄 我会救你的 - 快 约翰 想主义
Take this off of me!
把这玩意儿拿开！
This will likely upset her a bit!
这可能会惹毛它
No!
不 ！！！
Dolittle! Help!
多力特 救命啊！
Is he speaking dragon?
她说龙语吗?
You may be able to speak my language
你可能会说我的语言
but that does not make you
worthy of the fruit.
但这也不会让你配得上果实
I know protecting the Tree is your duty
我知道保护那颗树是你的职责
but you won't be able to continue
much longer
但是考虑到你搞的破坏以及你的痛苦
considering the damage you've taken
and the pain you're in.
你能不能不要再执着了
You know nothing of my pain.
你对我承受的痛苦一无所知
But I do. I had it as well.
我懂 我也经历过
The kind that doesn't come
from a bullet or a blade
那种痛苦不是来自枪炮和刀剑
but cuts much deeper.
但却伤得更深
And now in every moment, in every
movement you feel that pain again.
每时每刻 举手投足 你都能再次感受到痛苦
It's hard to carry on...
君失所爱者
...when you've lost the one you love.
……难续终矣
Just leave!
给我走！
- What just happened?
- Ah, broken hearts...
- 刚才发生了什么？ - 伤心人的事
What the heck are you doing here?
该死你在这干吗？
Don't worry guys, I got this.
We're both dragons.
别担心 各位 我们都是龙
Hey, just wondering
you know, dragon to dragon.
嘿 我好奇 你说 龙和龙之间
If you wouldn't mind telling me what...
如果你不介意告诉……
She's really mad, I'll wait
for whoever survives outside.
她很生气 我到外面去等着各位幸存者
John, let's just get out of here
while we still can.
约翰 我们得趁还能走就赶紧走
No. I think we are here to help her.
不 我觉得我们应该帮帮她
Yeah. We haven't got much time!
对 我们时间还多
I imagine it's a bit tender here.
我觉得这应该会比较棘手
I'm unarmed.
I pose no threat to you.
我没有武器 不会伤害你
Emotional stress over the years
has done damage to your stomach.
多年情绪积压已经损坏你的胃了
Get away from me!
给我走开！
You have severe infection of colon.
你结肠感染很严重
And if I don't manually fragment it
it will go septic.
如果我不给你做手术 会溃烂
And you won't be able to protect
anything anymore.
你再也不用守卫任何东西了
- That sounds like some tummy ache.
- I'll tell you what.
- 听起来像肚子疼 - 我跟你说啊
Give us five minutes.
给我们5分钟
If you don't feel better
you can fry us all--
如果你没有好转 你就把我们都烧了……
Stop talking! Just get on with it.
闭嘴！赶紧处理！
We have to get you on your side.
我们得帮你翻过去
We need to perform
an emergency extraction.
我们需要开展紧急手术
- Extraction? What are we pulling out?
- Go get it, Doc.
- 手术？我们要开始干什么？- 明白了 医生
- We got your back, Doc.
- It's showtime.
- 有我们在 医生 - 表演时刻到
Three, two, one. Turn!
三 二 一 翻！
Chee-Chee, chuck me the forceps.
吉吉 扔给我手术钳
- Knew it will come in handy. Told ya!
- Everybody knows what to do to do?
- 在手边的 告诉你了！ -大家都知道怎么做吧
- Just breathe.
- Works for me.
- 冷静  - 有我在
It's okay, just hold on to
my wing, sweetie. Dab-Dab's here.
很棒 拉着我的翅膀 嘎嘎陪你
Oy! You are my apprentice.
You keep her calm.
噢 你是我的学徒 你得让她冷静
Did you know that leek
is the national emblem of Wales?
你们知道吗？ 韭菜是威尔士的国徽
Very useful it is, too.
You might feel... a bit of pressure.
它也很有用 你可能会感到……有点压力
I got her.
有我在
Oh, good heavens!
噢 天呐
- Oh, no, you didn't.
- Oh my God!
- 噢 不 你没有 - 噢 老天爷
- Just clearing the way.
- Is that harmles?
- 清除开一条路 - 那是无害的？
You've got
the whole Spanish army in here!
这里大概会有一支西班牙军队
Give us a deep breath. Hold it.
深呼吸 抓住
- A word of warning...
- What's up, Doc?
- 警告你们啊…… - 怎么？ 医生
When we're removing the blockage...
Yoshi, now.
当我们疏通这里的时候…… 耀西 快
There may be
an initial release of wind.
这可能会刮一阵自来风
- Respect.
- It's all right. Nobody heard that.
- 天啊 - 没关系 没人看见
Nothing to be ashamed of.
We all do it. We are all animals.
没什么不好意思的 我们都会 我们都是动物
I can taste it!
我不行了
Okay, I'm back. What did I miss?
好的 我回来了 我错过了什么？
Oh my God!
噢 我的老天爷
- This is the big one!
- We're in the home stretch now!
- 这有个大家伙 - 开始冲刺
- Chee-Chee, get behind me.
- I'm with you, Doc. On your call.
- 吉吉 来我后面 - 我来了 医生
Blood rushing to my head.
Everything turning red.
血溅到我眼睛里了 一片血红
One last push, madam, if you please.
最后一次 拉 大家使劲
Thank you.
谢谢你们
- We did it!
- Team work makes the dream work.
- 我们成功了！ - 团队合作 梦想成真
That was the one. We did good.
这可真是的 我们做得很好
To put it simply, more leafy greens
and less armor in your diet.
简单说 以后多吃水果蔬菜 少吃盔甲
I've seen armies of every kind
but nothing like you.
我见过各种各样的人类 没有一个像你这样
What unites such a group of creatures?
你们是一群什么生物？
Well, we may not look it, right?
But somehow...
好吧 我们看起来不太一样 但是……
- ...we just belong together.
- Now let me help you.
- ……我们就很团结 - 现在我来帮你们吧
Lily would have loved it, John.
约翰 莉莉肯定会很喜欢的
We would never have found it
without her.
没有她我们永远也找不到
I just got the chills.
And I'm not even cold.
我竟然不寒而栗了
Thank you for showing me
the way, my love.
谢谢你指引我 我的至爱
*
威尔士诸神 佑我君王
and restore her, to a longer
continuance amongst us.
复以健体 永生长存
O Father of mercies
and Lord of all comfort--
永颂神明 以示感激
I'm sorry we couldn't save you
Your Majesty.
对不起 陛下 我们没能救你
It is with great sadness--
哀痛欲绝……
Wait a minute, I smell something.
It smells like...
等下 我闻到了 闻起来像……
- Hope!
- ...that I have to announce...
- 希望！- 我在此宣布……
- ...that the Queen is no longer--
- Somebody called a doctor?
-……女王…… - 有人叫医生了？
My mates! Very dramatic
entrance, boys. Well played.
我的伙伴！ 非常生动的出场  好样的
- We've arrived.
- Dolittle!
- 我们到了 - 多力特！
Clear a path, there isn't
a moment to waste!
让一让 时间紧急
I have procured that
what you said does not exist.
我有了你说不存在的
Behold, the fruit of the Eden Tree.
看呐 伊甸园树的果实
I said clear a path.
我说了都闪开
Seize them!
抓住他们!
Sorry.
对不起
- Go!
- Seize them!
- 快！ - 抓住他们！
You were born for this moment.
你就是为此而生的
I'm fine.
我能行
Mini, take flight!
小小鼠 飞吧
Go! Go!
快 快去
No! No!
不 不
Kevin's log. Day unknown.
凯文日志 不知道第几天了
The killing has ended.
Let there be life!
不再有杀戮了 拯救生命
Lady Rose.
萝丝小姐
Is that a giraffe in my bedchamber?
那是只长颈鹿在我的寝宫吗？
Yes!
是！
Oh, yes. And a polar bear, and a gorilla
噢 是的！ 还有一只北极熊、一头大猩猩
and a parrot and a duck, and ostrich.
一只鹦鹉、一只鸭子和一只鸵鸟
A humble thanks be to God!
感谢上帝啊
And well done, Doctor Dolittle.
干得好 多力特医生
Not quite done, are we?
还没完 对吧
Interesting, carry on, Sticks.
I'm all ears.
有趣的是 木棍 我有耳朵
What's that?
什么？
Sticks here agreed to stay behind
keep his 12 eyes on things.
木棍在这用它的十二只眼睛看到了
He's was just catching me up.
它刚跟我说了
Like all leaf insects, he speaks
in iterable phrases, and he states
就像所有的昆虫 它跟我说 它说
Lord Badgley did poison the Queen.
贝格利爵士想毒死女王
What? He did?
什么？他干的？
Really, Dolittle? This is too much.
真的吗？ 多力特 这也太了吧
You're certain?
Well, this should be the time.
你确定？ 是的 现在是时候了
No, I'm sorry
Sticks is quite adamant.
很抱歉 棍子坚持这样说
In his right pocket the vial.
瓶子在他右边的口袋你
That would be seven.
这都七个字了
In his right pocket the vial
of deathly nightshade.
噢 在他右边口袋里有暗夜龙葵花
Let's have a look, shall we?
我们可以看看吗？
You can't possibly believe
that he's talking to an insect.
你不能相信吧 它的昆虫告诉他的
Well, I've spoken to ladybugs
好吧 我跟昆虫女士说过了
making a wish before they fly away.
再她们飞走前许了个愿望
Let's have a look.
给我看看
No one messes with my family!
Take one more step and I'll rip you a--
没人可以欺负我家人 再走一步我就割开你的……
To the Tower with him.
把他带到堡垒里去
- Someone's been a bad boy.
- Come on.
- 有人使坏了 - 来吧
I don't know why you all standing there.
不知道你们为什么还站在这
Nobody's died. Leave me in peace.
没人会死 让我静静
You too.
你也是
Not you, Doctor Dolittle.
你别走 多力特医生
A moment, if you would please.
等一下 如果可以
Lady Rose, who is this person
and why is he staring at me?
萝丝小姐 他是谁？为什么盯着我看
He's Stubbins.
他是斯塔宾斯
I want to be an animal doctor.
我想当一个动物医生
He saved your life.
他救了你一命
Thank you.
It's good to have you back, doctor.
谢谢你 很高兴你在 医生
Polly!
波利
- Anything you'd like to say to me?
- You were right, I suppose.
-你想跟我说什么？- 你说得对 我觉得
It is nice to get out of the
house every once in a while.
每隔一段时间踏出家门走走真的很好
Stubbins, Mini! Enough, we have
far less important places to be.
斯塔宾斯 小小鼠 我们还有更重要的事
Our story ends the way it began.
我们故事就这样结束了 正如开始
I have a letter for Doctor Dolittle.
Somebody get me down!
我有一封多力特医生的信 放我下来
Mostly.
最后
（孔雀族群的交流沟通）
There once was a peculiar doctor.
有一个独特的医生
Who found he was
at his best when sharing
他发现他最擅长的事情
his extraordinary ability with others.
- Excellent.
当他展示他非凡的能力的时候 - 好样的
Soon, Doctor Dolittle re-opened his gates
as Lily would have wanted.
不久 多力特再次打开了大门 正如莉莉所愿
- Three more in the queue, again
- Copy that.
- 又来三个 - 收到
Dolittle discovered his place
in the world once again.
多力特向世界再次开放了他的世界
After all, it's only by helping others
that we can truly help ourselves.
毕竟 只有帮助他人才能真正帮助我们自己
Subtitles created by shanice3
www.pdoro.com
（中文字幕翻译/打轴：冷眼）
Edited by =tosem=
xiayuejin
（知识浅薄 如有疏忽 万望海涵）